Now, let's learn about searching for an element in array.
For example, if you are asked to find Element 40 in an array containing maybe it contains 40, maybe
not.
So the first case?
Wave is containing 40, so at index zero, we have 10 at Index one 20.
At the index to 30 attendees for a 30 40 Athens export is.
Now we need to search for Element 40.
We have this like iteration going through all the elements, and the check is the box inside the box,
which is for the equal to the element of the array.
It starts.
Yes, it's it finds that element 40 and save that the element in the box that it contains is equal to
the element of the array.
OK, so it returned one or the 10 true or whatever.
But basically this is returning one or returning true is is the returning type of the method that if
you ask it to right now, let's see the other scenario.
You find the Element 100 in this array, we have 10, 20, 30, 40 and 50 100 is not found.
It put one hundred inside the box that it contains and start searching the Adam.
It will return minus one or return false.
OK.
This is the algorithm of searching an element or searching searching for an element into an array.
OK, now let's go and implement this into coding.
OK.
For searching, we need to make an array.
Sorry, and a method called search that took into the Bernie meter and array and in size and in key,
we need to search for that key.
OK.
So we start by for a always when dealing with areas like accessing oil and preventing all elements like
searching, like adding, inserting at specific position, all the think about using the for loop.
This is the trick behind using addres.
OK, so.
This implementation of a box that and a arrow that starts and iterating through all elements and start
comparing what that in box and what is an element if they are equal, it will return.
One is implemented into an array that starts from zero and reach reaches a less than size and i plus
plus if the array of I equal equal to key.
So if we have an array at the array at specific index, equal equal to the key that it contains return
one.
So we start searching for the key.
If the key equal equal to or array at index are equal, equal to the key, then return one.
Let us start by using this iteration.
At Index I at first iteration at the start, if it I less then sighs, yes, through the key equal to
the array at index one.
No, I + + one at iteration one is the key is not equal to the array.
At Index, I won the second iteration.
The array at Index two is not equal to there is not equal to the key at the third iteration.
The key is is equal to the array at Index three.
So this will result in searching and returning true.
OK, so this is returning true or returning one?
If not, if this not happens, or if the 40 is not found, we would return minus one.
OK.
Best case scenario is finding the element at index zero.
Think about searching for this array inside this array of four element equal to 10.
It start from an index from index zero.
It found that element at index zero.
This is off one because it may one.
Iteration, the worst case scenario is often finding the element at last position.
Think about searching for this array inside this array for Element 50.
It will be founded and go through all the elements in order to find the element.
50.
OK, this is the algorithm behind searching for an array or searching for an element into array.
I need from you to write this down.
The coding and the complex and.